Finding aid for Thomas Yoder papers, 1967-1991
Bentley Historical Library
- Sound Recordings
  - Audiocassette Tapes
    - Recordings of conference talks and prayer meetings, 1969-1972
      - Jim Cavnar, "Spiritual Power In the Body of Christ"; Community Day, 2nd Talk, 1971 May 01; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 7)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-99-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Jim Cavnar talk entitled "Spiritual Power in the Body of Christ.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-99-2]; mp3 file; (Recording of Jim Cavnar talk entitled "Spiritual Power in the Body of Christ.")
      - [Talks from Conferences] (Men's Weekend) "I am the bread of life", 1971 November 06, 1971 November 11; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 7)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-100-1]; mp3 file; (Labeled as "Not Good" on cassette. Talk from Men's Weekend Retreat entitled "I am the bread of life.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-100-2]; mp3 file; (Labeled as "Not Good" on cassette. Talk from Men's Weekend Retreat entitled "I am the bread of life.")
      - [Talks from Conferences] Ralph Martin "Being servants of God"; Steve Clark "Being Soldiers of Christ", 1971 November 05-06; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 7)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-101-1]; mp3 file; (Ralph Martin talk entitled "Being servants of God.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-101-2]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Being Soldiers of Christ.")
      - [Talks from conferences] Doug Gavrilides "Love for God", 1971 November 06; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 7)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-102-1]; mp3 file; (Doug Gavrilides talk entitled "Love for God.")
      - [Talks from conferences] Jack Bromback "Christian family life", 1971 November 21; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-103-1]; mp3 file; (Jack Bromback talk entitled "Christian Family Life.")
      - Steve Clark "Community order", [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-104-1]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Community Order.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-104-2]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Community Order.")
      - Coordinator's meeting, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-105-1]; mp3 file; (Attached note] "Erase" Meeting between members of the church on planning and organizational issues.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-105-2]; mp3 file; (Attached note] "Erase" Meeting between members of the church on planning and organizational issues.)
      - Mike Donnelly; Interviews, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-106-1]; mp3 file; (Mike Donnelly interviewing members of The Word of God)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-106-2]; mp3 file; (Mike Donnelly interviewing members of The Word of God)
      - Jim Manney interviews, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-107-1]; mp3 file; (Jim Manney (TRY))
      - [Interviews] Derek Prince - Erase, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-108-1]; mp3 file; (Derek Prince discussing the Charismatic movement.)
      - [Interviews] Derek Prince interview with Ralph Martin, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-109-1]; mp3 file; (Derek Prince discussing the Charismatic movement.)
      - Steve Clark discussion on Federation, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-110-1]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark discussing the Charismatic movement.)
      - Community Songs, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-111-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of hymns sung by the church. "Priestly People", "All of My Life", "Praise, Honor, and Glory", "Priestly People", "Sanctus", "They'll Know We Are Christians", "I Will Arise", "Romans 8", "Allelulia", "Psalm 118", impromptu singing.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-111-2]; mp3 file; (Recording of hymns sung by the church; "The Rest of Our Lives", "Sanctus", "We Shall Overcome" "Psalm 118", "Fill My House", "When You're Looking for the Lord", "God and Man at the Table Are Sat Down", "Psalm 8-9/ I am the Bread of Life.")
      - Music for Prayer Meetings, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-112-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; A series of hymns and other musical pieces used at prayer meetings.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-112-2]; mp3 file; (Tape 1; A series of hymns and other musical pieces used at prayer meetings.)
      - Music for Prayer Meetings, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-113-1]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; A series of hymns and other musical pieces used at prayer meetings.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-113-2]; mp3 file; (Tape 2; A series of hymns and other musical pieces used at prayer meetings.)
      - Music Tape #1 - Elieen Cavner, [Undated]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-114-1]; mp3 file; (Image for 89464-SR-114-2.jpg correlates to tape for this entry, but the insert correlates to 89464-SR-116. Recording of hymns sung by the church. "How Good It Is" Ps: 133; Ps (is.); "Jesus, Jesus My Lord"; The Spirit of God Is Upon Me; How Great Thou Art; 1; unknown hymn; "Sing to the Lord All You Nations" Psalm 69?; unknown psalm; "Let The Peoples Praise You, O God"; "Clap Your Hands All You Peoples"; Psalm 110?; Great to Us O Lord; "I Place All My Trust In You My God"; "Send Forth Your Light and Your Truth"; We Long for You, O Lord; unknown hymn; It's A Brand New Day; "All You Nations Sing That Your Joy to the Lord"; There Is A Balm in Gilead; "Israel Relyon Yahweh" Ps. 131; Sing Praise to the Lord, Allelluia; Ps. 118.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-114-2]; mp3 file; (Image for 89464-SR-114-2.jpg correlates to tape for this entry, but the insert correlates to 89464-SR-116. Recording of hymns sung by the church; Jacob's Song; Romans 8; "As The Doe Longs for Running Streams"; "Away They Went With Keeping"; "I Will Arise"; The Spirit Is A-Movin'; I Am The Resurrection; The King of Glory; "Song of Good News" (Ps. ?); We Are One in the Spirit; Canticle of the Gift; Priestly People; Brand New Canticle; Canticle of the 3 Young Men; All of My Life; There Is None Like Him; Praise Him.)
      - Covenant ceremony I; II, 1970 September 28, 1970 November 23; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-115-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-115-2]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
      - Music Tape #2 - Eileen Cavner, 1970 October 14, 1970 April 19; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-116-1]; mp3 file; (Liner notes are located with 89464-SR-114-2.jpg. Recording of hymns sung by the church. God Gives His People Strength; "Jesus Is A Lovin' Lord"; unknown hymn; Just A Closer Walk With Thee Glorious God; "Praise, Honor, and Glory"; Fill my House Unto The Fullest; The Rest of Our Lives; Alleluia, Praise the Lord! (?); They That Wait Upon the Lord; Alleluia (9x); Come and Go With Me; "How Good Is The Lord"; Ps. 118 (or 119); Simple Gifts; Domine Non Sum Dignus.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-116-2]; mp3 file; (Liner notes are located with 89464-SR-114-2.jpg. Recording of hymns sung by the church. Hole in the Sky; "All You Nations, Sing Out Your Joy To The Lord"; There Is A Balm in Gilead; Ps. 131; (Sing Praise to the Lord) unknown psalm; When The Spirit Moves You; When You're Looking for the Lord; Psalm 133; Jacob's Song; unknown hymn; Canticle of the Gift; Grant to Us, O Lord (unknown psalm); As the Doe Longs for Running Streams (unknown psalm); Away They Went With Weeping; I Will Arise.)
      - Father E. O'Connor "Catholic Charismatic Renewal and Traditional Sacramentality", 1971 January; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-117-1]; mp3 file; (Father E. O'Connor talk entitled "Catholic Charismatic Renewal and Traditional Sacramentality.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-117-2]; mp3 file; (Father E. O'Connor talk entitled "Catholic Charismatic Renewal and Traditional Sacramentality.")
      - [General Community Gathering] Steve Clark "The Covenant", 1971 March 20; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-118-1]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "The Covenant.")
      - [Fall Conference] "Talent Show", 1971 September 11; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-119-1]; mp3 file; (A series of songs performed by members of the congregation at a talent show.)
      - [Community Weekend] Sharing Session, 1972 March 19, 1972 April 20; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-120-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
      - Fall Conference Prophecies and Tells, 1972 September 08; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-121-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of fall conference opening sessions.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-121-2]; mp3 file; (Conference talk by Ralph Martin entitled: "State of the Word of God.")
      - [Prayer Meeting], 1972 May 18; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-122-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
      - [Prayer Meeting], 1972 May 28; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-123-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
      - [Prayer Meeting], 1972 June 08; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-124-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
      - [Prayer Meeting], 1972 June 11; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-125-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-125-2]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
      - [Prayer Meeting], 1972 June 15; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-126-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
      - [Prayer Meeting], 1972 June 18; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1; no Side 2], [89464-SR-127-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a prayer meeting and sermons.)
      - [General Community Gathering], 1973 March 25; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-128-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-128-2]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
      - 6th Anniversary Celebration, 1973 November 18; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-129-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing in celebration of the community's 6th anniversary.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-129-2]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing in celebration of the community's 6th anniversary.)
      - [General Community Gathering] Steve Clark "Criticism", 1975 July; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-130-1]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talking at a General Community Gathering. Talk is titled "Criticism.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-130-2]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talking at a General Community Gathering. Talk is titled "Criticism.")
      - [General Community Gathering] Prayer Meeting, 1975 November 16; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-131-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-131-2]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
      - [General Community Gathering], 1975 December 07; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-132-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-132-2]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
      - [General Community Gathering], 1975 December 18; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-133-1]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-133-2]; mp3 file; (A recording of a series of prayer meetings, ceremonies, and hymn singing.)
      - Living in Christian Community #2 Steve Clark "Order in the Christian Community", 1976 February 15; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-134-1]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Order in the Christian Community.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-134-2]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Order in the Christian Community.")
      - Living in Christian Community #3 Steve Clark "Personal Headship and Submission", 1976 February 22; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-135-1]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Personal Headship and Submission.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-135-2]; mp3 file; (Steve Clark talk entitled "Personal Headship and Submission.")
      - Retreat, Jerry Rauch "Listening to the Word of God", 1976 March 07; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-136-1]; mp3 file; (Jerry Rauch talk at retreat entitled "Listening to the Word of God.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-136-2]; mp3 file; (Jerry Rauch talk at retreat entitled "Listening to the Word of God.")
      - General Community Gathering Bruce Yocum "Prophecy", 1977 August 14; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-137-1]; mp3 file; (Bruce Yocum at General Community Gathering with talk entitled "Prophecy.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-137-2]; mp3 file; (Bruce Yocum at General Community Gathering with talk entitled "Prophecy.")
      - General Community Gathering Jim McFadden; Bruce Yocum "New Developments", 1977 September 25; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-138-1]; mp3 file; (Jim McFadden talk and Bruce Yocum giving a talk entitled "New Developments.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-138-2]; mp3 file; (Jim McFadden talk and Bruce Yocum giving a talk entitled "New Developments.")
      - General Community Gathering Jim McFadden; Berg Ghezzi "Learning About Intercession", 1977 October 09; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-139-1]; mp3 file; (Jim McFadden talk and Berg Ghezzi giving a talk entitled "Learning About Intercession.")
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-139-2]; mp3 file; (Jim McFadden talk and Berg Ghezzi giving a talk entitled "Learning About Intercession.")
      - Anita Rauch Testimony on The Word of God, [1978 April]; Audio Cassette, Compact Cassette, 1 7/8 ips (Box 8)
        - [Side 1], [89464-SR-140-1]; mp3 file; (Anita Rauch discusses her experiences in The Word of God community including living arrangements, dating, and authority and exclusion in the community as well as the treatment of women.)
        - [Side 2], [89464-SR-140-2]; mp3 file; (Anita Rauch discusses her experiences in The Word of God community including living arrangements, dating, and authority and exclusion in the community as well as the treatment of women.)
  - Reel-to-reel tapes
    - Notre Dame Conference, Prophecies, 1972; 5 in. (Box 8)
    - 7 inch, various speeds
      - Community Weekend, September 1970; 2 tapes (Box 8)
      - Prayer meeting talk, Ralph Martin "It Just Doesn't Fit", January 21, 1971 (Box 8)
      - Saturday talk at Fall Conference of Word of God, September 9, 1972; 3 3/4 ips (Box 8)
      - Sunday talk at Fall Conference of Word of God, September 10, 1972 (Box 8)
      - 5th Anniversary celebration, November 22, 1972; 49:24 min.; 7 1/2 ips; 2 track (Box 8)
      - 6th anniversary celebration, October 1973 (Box 8)
        (copy from cassette)
      - CPF, Phil O'Mara, 1974 (Box 8)
      - G.C.C. "Criticism", July 13, 1975 (Box 8)
      - Ralph Martin, August 22, 1976 (Box 8)
      - Fall Word of God Conference, 1976; 2 tapes (Box 8)
      - Interview with Phil O'Mara, February 1977 (Box 8)
      - Music for Prayer Meetings, 3 3/4 ips (Box 8)
    - 10 inch various speeds (Box 9)
      - 1978 Community Conference (Saturday Morning Session) -- "Being a People of Faith" Part I, Bruce Yocum speaker, June 3, 1978 (Box 9)
      - International Conference (Dublin), 1978; 90 min.; 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track
        - Evangelization I, speakers: Ranaghan, Ferry, Hume, Parmentier, 10 in.; 3 3/4 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
        - Evangelization II, speakers: Ranaghan, Talavera, Emmanuel Cmty., 10 in.; 3 3/4 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - International Missionary Conference (Dublin), 1978
        - Basic Christian Communities, speakers; Kevin O'Boyle, Guitterez, 10 in.; 3 3/4 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - Steubenville Leaders Conference, 1978
        - Saturday Morning Session, speakers: Shields, Brees (Box 9)
      - "Healing Hurts from God" speaker Fr. Linn, 1978; 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - "Gathering a People" speaker Judy Tidings, 1978; 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - Wednesday morning conference speakers Father Bertoluchi, Father Scanlon, Bobbie Cauner, 1977; 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - Tuesday morning, "Seeking Vision for Local Church", speaker Father Scanlon, 1979; 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - General Community Gathering, December 12, 1977; 10 in.; 3 3/4 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - "Love and sexuality", 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
      - Anniversary celebration GCG and piano at dinner, December 11, 1977; 10 in.; 3 3/4 ips; 1/2 track (Box 9)
        ("poor playing")
      - Father Herb Schneider Conference, 10 in.; 7 1/2 ips; 1/2 track
        - July 3, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 5, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 6, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 7, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 9, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 10, 1984, 2 reels (Box 10)
        - July 11, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 12, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 13, 1984 (Box 10)
        - July 14, 1984 (Box 10)
      - Unidentified, 11 reels (Box 11)
- Videotapes
  The videotapes are of a four part series given by Ralph Martin on the holiness of God.
  - Holiness messages, Ralph Martin, 1986; vhs videotapes
    - The Holiness of God (Box 11)
    - Our Encounter with the Holiness of God (Box 11)
    - Growth in Holiness (Box 11)
    - Holiness and Suffering (Box 11)
- Microfilm
  - Various records, 2 reels (Box 11)
    (These microfilm reels were made in 1978 when Thomas Yoder requested that his papers be returned to him; he allowed the library to make a microfilm copy of the files; in 1982 he returned the papers to the library; this microfilm is a copy of the files now dispersed throughout boxes 1-6)